A Finding Aid to the Robert Smithson and Nancy Holt Papers, 1905-1987, bulk 1952-1987, in the Archives of American Art AAA.smitrobe
Archives of American Art
- Writings, 1959-1975; Series 4; 1.1 Linear feet Boxes 2-3
  - By Robert Smithson, circa 1959-1973; 4.1
    Writings by Smithson consists of 73 handwritten and typescript outlines, essay drafts, and lectures Smithson wrote from the 1960s to 1973. The majority of these writings explore his thoughts on contemporary art and artists. Through the theoretical frameworks that incorporate history, linguistics, aesthetics, literature, and media studies, Smithson examines historical and contemporary art's evolving concepts of interpretation and meaning, and specifically, the effect capitalism, nature and the environment, minimalism, and conceptual absences were having on his own art.
    Essays of note include "The Crystal Land" (1966), "Cultural Confinement" (ca. 1972), "Frederick Law Olmstead and the Dialectical Landscape," (ca. 1973), "Incidents of Mirror Travel in the Yucatan" (ca. 1969), and "See the Monuments of Passaic New Jersey" (1970).
    The subseries also includes six notebooks that record project ideas, fragments of essays, and letter drafts; a series of 21 poems written by Smithson on Christian/religious themes; and miscellaneous handwritten and typescript notes on art and film. Notebooks I and VI include notes by Nancy Holt.
    - "Abstract Mannerism,", circa 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - "Art and Dialectics,", circa 1971 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - "Art and the Political Whirlpool or the Politics of Disgust,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - "Art and Time,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - "Art and Truth,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - "Art Through the Camera's Eye,", circa 1971 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - "Artist as Site-Seer,", circa 1966-1967 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - "Better Homes and Industries,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - "Broken Circle, Emmen, Holland,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - "Can Man Survive?,", circa 1969 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - "Cinematic Atopia,", circa 1971 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - "Collossal Nullifications,", circa 1966 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - "Critoid Menace,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - "Crystal Land,", 1966 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - "Cultural Confinement,", circa 1972 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - "Dialectic of Site and Non-Site,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - "Domain of the Great Bear,", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - "Earth Art and Reclamation,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - "Earth Projects (A Sedimentation of the Mind),", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - "Ecology and the Incest Taboo,", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - "Economics of Self in Nature and Art,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - "Establishment,", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "Esthetics of Disappointment,", circa 1966 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - "Fiction and Language in Art,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - "First Louse on the Tip of a Penis,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Frederick Law Olmstead and the Dialectical Landscape,", circa 1973 (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - "From Ivan the Terrible to Roger Corman or Paradoxes of Conduct in Mannerism as Reflected in the Cinema,", circa 1967 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - "Hidden Trails in Art,", 1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - "Hotel Palenque,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - "Iconography of Desolation,", 1961 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - "Illustrations of Catastrophe and Remote Times,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - "Incidents of Mirror-Travel in the Yucatan,", circa 1969 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - "Interstellar Flit,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - "Lamentations of the Paroxysmal Artist,", circa 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Letter to Michael Fried, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - "Look,", circa 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - "Minus Twelve,", circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - "Modular Properties in Structural Art,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - "Museum of Language in the Vicinity of Art,", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "Nature and Abstraction,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - "New Monuments and Entropy,", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - "Note on the Division of Esthetics,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - "Notes for the Tape Recorder,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - On Donald Judd, Drafts and Fragments, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - On Donald Judd, Complete Draft, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - On Donald Judd, Copy B, circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    - "Outline for Yale Symposium: Against Absolute Categories,", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    - "Paragraph from a Fugitive Artist's Journal,", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    - "Pathetic Fallacy in Esthetics,", circa 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    - "Picturable Situations and Infra-Maps,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    - "Pointless Vanishing Points,", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    - "Primary Envelopment,", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    - "Production for Production's Sake,", circa 1972 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    - "Quasi-Infinities and the Waning of Space,", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    - "Recent Site Developments,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    - "Refutation of Historical Humanism,", circa 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    - "Restorations of Prehistory,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    - "Search for the Elusive Edge,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    - "Secrets of the Ambulatories,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    - "Secrets of the Dome,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    - "See the Monuments of Passaic, New Jersey," Draft, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    - "See the Monuments of Passaic, New Jersey,", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    - "Shape of the Future and Memory,", circa 1966 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    - "Sites and Settings,", circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    - "Small Test for Jo Baer,", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    - "Some Void Thoughts on Museums,", circa 1967 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    - "Sonsbeek Unlimited - Art as an Ongoing Development,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    - "Space, The Mirror of Time,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    - "Strata, A Geophotographic Fiction,", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    - "Toward the Development of an Air Terminal Site,", circa 1967 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - "Towards a Pornographic Art Criticism,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    - "Two Attitudes Toward the City,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    - "What is an Art Show? A Paper Tiger,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    - "What Really Spoils Michelangelo's Sculpture,", circa 1966-1967 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - "X Factor in the New Art,", circa 1966 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    - Notebook I, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 61)
    - Notebook II, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 62)
    - Notebook III, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 63)
    - Notebook IV, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 64)
    - Notebook V, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 65)
    - Notebook VI, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 66)
    - Poems, circa 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 67)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Typescript, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 68)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, Handwritten, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 69)
    - Miscellaneous Notes, On Films, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 3, Folder 70)
  - By Others, 1962-1975; 4.1
    Writings by others includes unpublished draft versions of essays and fictional works sent to Smithson and Holt by friends, colleagues, and students of art criticism. Smithson is the topic of two personal reminiscences by Carl Andre and Jack Thibeau and seven academic essays examining his work and influence.
    The scholarly essays include Janet Kardon's "Robert Smithson's Unrealized Projects," William Lipke's "Dialectics of Place: Some Reflections on Robert Smithson's Mirror Project," and Joseph Masheck's "Smithson's Earth: Notes and Retrievals." Though there is no attributed author of the essay "Non-Sites," the draft has been edited by Robert Smithson.
    Other writings include two project proposals by Dan Graham, a project proposal by Terry Atkinson, writings and a speech by Dan Flavin, and a draft of "Idea Art" (1968) by Howard Junker.
    - Andre, Carl, [On Robert Smithson], 1975 (Box 3, Folder 71)
    - Atkinson, Terry, "Three Boxes,", circa 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 72)
    - Baker, Kenneth, "Note on Criticism as Fiction,", circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 73)
    - Fischer, Candace, "Labyrinth,", circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 74)
    - Flavin, Dan, [Excerpt from a Letter and a Record Entry], 1966; 1963 (Box 3, Folder 75)
    - Flavin, Dan, "Speech for the Senior and Graduate School Students at the Rhode Island School of Design,", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 76)
    - Graham, Dan, "Dislocations,", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 77)
    - Graham, Dan, "TV Camera/Monitor Performance,", 1970 (Box 3, Folder 78)
    - Junker, Howard, "Idea Art,", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 79)
    - Kaprow, Allan, "Where Art Thou, Sweet Muse? (I'm Hung Up at the Whitney),", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 80)
    - Kardon, Janet, "Robert Smithson's Unrealized Projects,", circa 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 81)
    - Kubler, George, [On Prime Objects and Replications], From The Shape of Time, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 82)
    - Lipke, William C., "Dialectics of Place: Some Reflections on Robert Smithson's Mirror Project" (Cayuga Salt Mine Project), circa 1969 (Box 3, Folder 83)
    - Masheck, Joseph, [Annotated Chronology of Smithson Projects, 1964-1973], circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 84)
    - Masheck, Joseph, "Smithson's Earth: Notes and Retrievals,", 1974 (Box 3, Folder 85)
    - Mussman, Toby, "Alchemist,", 1967 (Box 3, Folder 86)
    - Mussman, Toby, "Pierrot-Le-Fou - Godard as Godard,", 1968 (Box 3, Folder 87)
    - O'Doherty, Brian, "Less Known and Unknown: An Exhibition of 35 Painters,", circa 1965 (Box 3, Folder 88)
    - Oster, Gerald, "What's Op?,", 1966 (Box 3, Folder 89)
    - Robbin, Anthony, "Some Common Misconceptions About Smithson's Conceptual Art,", circa 1968 (Box 3, Folder 90)
    - Robbin, Anthony, "Zen,", circa 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 91)
    - Rubenfeld, Florence, [On Robert Smithson], 1974 (Box 3, Folder 92)
    - Shafrazi, Tony, "Thats It,", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 93)
    - Stitelman, Paul, "Light and Video: Contemporary Art and Technology,", circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 94)
    - Swenson, Gene, "Way of Art: A Comedy in Six Scenes,", circa 1960s-1970s (Box 3, Folder 95)
    - Thibeau, Jack, "Los Cines,", 1972 (Box 3, Folder 96)
    - Thibeau, Jack, [On Robert Smithson], circa 1970s (Box 3, Folder 97)
    - Unknown, "Non-Sites,", circa 1969 (Box 3, Folder 98)
- Project Files, circa 1950s-1982; Series 5; 6.5 Linear feet Boxes 4-5, Boxes 17-18, OV 20, OV 22-26, OV 36, RD 28-30, RD 32-35
  Project files contain correspondence, project instructions, diagrams and sketches, research materials, photographic material, and maps related to over 50 of Smithson's artworks. These include concepts, proposed projects, sculptures, non-sites, and earthwork projects, including Spiral Jetty, Broken Circle, and Spiral Hill.
  The series also includes miscellaneous textual and graphic research material collected by Smithson but unrelated to any specific art project.
  The series has been arranged alphabetically by project name.
  - 400 Seattle Horizons, Seattle, [Washington], 1969 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - "Aerial Art,", circa 1969 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Alogon, 1966-1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Amarillo Ramp, Amarillo, Texas, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, F1
  - Asphalt Rundown, L'attico, Rome, Italy, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Broken Circle and Spiral Hill, Emmen, Holland, 1971-1982; 4 Folders (Box 4, Folder 6-9)
    Oversized material housed in OV 22 and RD 28
  - Broken Map, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    Oversized material housed in RD 29
  - Central Park (Frederick Law Olmstead), New York City, New York, 1972; 3 Folders (Box 4, Folder 11-13)
  - Circular Ramp (Promontory), circa 1970s (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Coastal Crescents, Salton Sea Project, California, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Concrete Pour, Chicago, Illinois, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Earth Map for Mexico (Gondwanaland), 1969 (Box 4, Folder 17)
    Oversized material housed in OV 22
  - "Eliminator,", 1964 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - First Upside-Down Tree, Alfred, New York, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Florida Projects, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Florida Projects, Hypothetical Continent of Lemuria, Sanibel Island, Florida, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Florida Projects, Mirror Shore, Sanibel Island, Florida, 1969-1971 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Flows and Pours, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 23)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, F2 and RD 32
  - Force-Findings of the Termites, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Gyrostasis, 1968-1972 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - "Hum,", circa 1965 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Hypothetical Continent in Stone: Cathaysia, Alfred, New York, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - "Interpolation of the Enantiomorphic Chambers,", circa 1966 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Island of Broken Glass, Vancouver, Canada, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 29)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, F3 and RD 29
  - Lake Crescents, Forest Park, Illinois, 1970-1973 (Box 4, Folder 30)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, F3
  - Lake Edge Crescents, Ohio, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Mirror Displacement, Cayuga Salt Mine Project, Ithica, New York, 1968-1969; 4 Folders (Box 4, Folder 32-35)
  - Mirror Displacements, England, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Mirror Project, Amsterdam, Holland, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Mirror Project, Rome, Italy, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - "Monument" (Film Project), circa 1967 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Monuments of Passaic, Passaic, New Jersey, 1967-1968; 4 Folders (Box 4, Folder 40-43)
  - "Mud Pool Project,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - New Jersey Projects, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, F4
  - New Jersey Projects, Chain Letter, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - New Jersey Projects, Map of Broken Glass, Atlantis, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - New Jersey Projects, Mirror Trail, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - New Jersey Projects, Mirror Wedge, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - New Jersey Projects, Urination Map of the Constellation Hydra, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - "Non-Site #2 (Based on Weehawken Quadrangle Map, New Jersey-New York,", 1968 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - "Non-Site #3, Indoor Earthwork - Rock Fragments from Franklin, New Jersey" (Franklin Mineral Dump), 1966-1968; 4 Folders (Box 4, Folder 52-55)
  - Non-Site, California-Nevada (Double Non-Site), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Non-Site, California-Nevada (Double Non-Site, Baker Lava), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Non-Site, California-Nevada (Double Non-Site, Obsidian Site), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Non-Site, California-Nevada (Double Non-Site, Sand and Gypsum Site), 1968 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - Non-Site, Essen Soil and Mirrors, Essen, Germany, 1969 (Box 4, Folder 60)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, F5
  - Non-Site, Line of Wreckage, Bayonne, New Jersey, 1968-1969; 4 Folders (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    Oversized material housed in OV 22 and RD 33
  - Non-Site, Mono Lake, California, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, F5 and RD 33
  - Non-Site, Palisades, Edgewater, New Jersey, 1968-1969 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Non-Site, Pine Barrens, New Jersey, 1968-1969; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 7-8)
  - Non-Site (Mica), Portland, Connecticut, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Non-Site, (Slag), Oberhausen, Germany, 1968; 5 Folders (Box 5, Folder 10-14)
  - Non-Site, (Slag), Oberhausen, Germany, 1968; 5 Folders (Box 5, Folder 15-19)
  - Non-Site (Slate), Bangor, Pennsylvania, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Partially Buried Woodshed, Kent State University, Kent, Ohio, 1969-1975; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 21-22)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, F6
  - "Predictable Model for Unpredictable Project,", circa 1966 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Proposal for Earthworks and Landmarks, Dallas-Fort Worth Air Terminal, Texas, 1967- 1969 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    Oversized material housed in Box 17, F6 and OV 23
  - "Proposal for Seven Aerial Pavements,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - "Proposal for the Detection of Approximate Period Quality,", circa 1966 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - "Proposal for the Venezuelan Exposition Art in the Wilderness,", circa 1960s-1973 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Proposed Mining Reclamation Projects, 1972-1973; 5 Folders (Box 5, Folder 28-32)
    Oversized material housed in Box 18, F1
  - "Pulverizations,", 1967 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Quicksand Pool, Alfred, New York, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - "Short Description of Two Mirrored Crystal Structures,", circa 1965 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Six Stops on a Section, New York - New Jersey, 1968-1969; 3 Folders (Box 5, Folder 36-38)
    Oversized material housed in Box 18, F1 and OV 23
  - Spiral Jetty, Great Salt Lake, Utah, 1969-1972; 5 Folders (Box 5, Folder 39-43)
  - Spiral Jetty, Great Salt Lake, Utah, 1969-1972; 5 Folders (Box 5, Folder 44-48)
    Oversized materials housed in Box 18, F2, OV 23 and RD 34
  - Spiral Jetty, Great Salt Lake, Utah, 1969-1972; 5 Folders (Box 5, Folder 49-53)
  - Tailing Pond, Creede, Colorado, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 54)
    Oversized materials housed in OV 23
  - Yucatan Projects, Yucatan, Mexico, 1968-1969; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 55-56)
    Oversized material housed in Box 18, F3
  - Unidentified Project, Brooklyn Museum, Brooklyn, New York, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Unidentified Projects, circa 1966-1973 (Box 5, Folder 58)
    Oversized material housed in Box 18, F3 and OV 24, and RD 29
  - Unidentified Proposed Project Maps, circa 1960s-1973 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Images, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 60)
    Oversized material housed in Box 18, F4
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Maps, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 61)
    Oversized material housed in OV 20, OVs 24 - 26, OV 36, RD 30, and RD 35
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Photographs, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Text, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Amarillo Ramp; Circular Ramp (Promontory); Coastal Crescents; and Florida Projects, circa 1969-1970s (Box 17, Folder 1)
    Oversized materials from Box 4, F4, F13-14, and F19
  - Flows and Pours, 1969 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 4, F22
  - Island of Broken Glass; Lake Crescents (Illinois); Mirror Displacement (Cayuga Salt Mine Project); and Mirror Project (Rome, Italy), 1968-1973 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    Oversized materials from Box 4, F28-29, F31, and F37
  - New Jersey Projects (Urination Map of the Constellation Hydra), 1969 (Box 17, Folder 4)
    Oversized materials from Box 4, F45 and F50
  - Non-Site, Essen Soil and Mirrors; Non-Site, Mono Lake; Non-Site, Palisades; and Non-Site, (Slag; Oberhausen, Germany), 1968-1969; and Box 5, F5-F6, and F10 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Partially Buried Woodshed; and Proposal for Earthworks and Landmarks (Dallas-Fort Worth Air Terminal), 1967-1975 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    Oversized materials from Box 5, F21 and F24
  - Proposed Mining Reclamation Projects; Quicksand Pool; and Six Stops on a Section, 1968-1973 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Oversized materials from Box 5, F28, F34, and F36
  - Spiral Jetty, 1969-1972 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Oversized material from Box 5, F44
  - Yucatan Projects; Unidentified Projects, 1966-1973 (Box 18, Folder 3)
    Oversized materials from Box 5, F55 and F58
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Images, circa 1950s-1970s (Box 18, Folder 4)
    Oversized material from Box 5, F60
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Maps, circa 1950s-1970s (Box OV 20)
    Oversized material from Box 5, F61
  - Broken Circle and Spiral Hill; Earth Map for Mexico (Gondwanaland); Mirror Displacements (England); Non-Site, California-Nevada (Double Non-Site); Non-Site, Line of Wreckage; and Non-Site, Pine Barrens, 1968-1982; and Box 5, F1 and F7 (Box OV 22)
  - Proposal for Earthworks and Landmarks (Dallas-Fort Worth Air Terminal); Six Stops on a Section; Spiral Jetty; and Tailing Pond, 1967-1973 (Box OV 23)
    Oversized materials from Box 5, F24, F36, F44, and F54
  - Unidentified Projects; and Miscellaneous Research Material, Maps, circa 1950s-1970s (Box OV 24)
    Oversized material from Box 5, F58 and F61
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Maps, circa 1950s-1970s (Box OV 25-26)
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Maps, circa 1950s-1970s (Box OV 36)
  - Broken Circle and Spiral Hill, 1971-1982 (Box RD 28)
    Oversized material from Box 4, F6
  - Broken Map; Island of Broken Glass; and Unidentified Projects, circa 1966-1973; and Box 5, F58 (Box RD 29)
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Maps, circa 1950s-1970s (Box RD 30)
  - Flows and Pours, 1969 (Box RD 32)
  - Non-Site, Line of Wreckage; and Non-Site, Mono Lake, 1968-1969 (Box RD 33)
    Oversized materials from Box 5, F1 and F5
  - Spiral Jetty, 1969-1972 (Box RD 34)
  - Miscellaneous Research Material, Maps, circa 1950s-1970s (Box RD 35)
- Personal Business Records, circa 1967-1970s; Series 6; 4 Folders Box 5
  Personal business records include gallery related loan arrangements and receipts for miscellaneous art supplies.
  The series has been arranged alphabetically by organization.
  - American Federation of Arts, 1967 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - John Daniels Gallery, circa 1960s (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Receipts, circa 1968-1970s; 2 Folders (Box 5, Folder 66-67)
- Financial Records, 1962-1972; Series 7; 1 Linear feet Box 6
  Financial records include tax forms and preparation documents, including cancelled checks, receipts, statements, and related correspondence.
  The series has been arranged chronologically by document type.
  - Cancelled Checks, Holt, 1964-1969; 7 Folders (Box 6, Folder 1-7)
  - Cancelled Checks, Smithson, 1962-1969; 6 Folders (Box 6, Folder 8-13)
  - Receipts, 1965; 2 Folders (Box 6, Folder 14-15)
  - Stocks, 1964-1971; 8 Folders (Box 6, Folder 16-23)
  - Tax Documentation and Forms, 1963-1967; 7 Folders (Box 6, Folder 24-30)
  - Tax Documentation and Forms, 1968-1972; 6 Folders (Box 6, Folder 31-36)
- Printed Material, 1955-1985; Series 8; 5.6 Linear feet Boxes 7-11, Box 18, RD 31
  Printed materials include books, clippings, and periodicals related to Smithson, either containing writings or sketches by him, or containing articles reviewing his work. While some of the clippings review Smithson's exhibitions and work, the bulk of the clippings are on the general topics of contemporary art trends, earth art, and emerging artists.
  Exhibition announcements and catalogs are of Smithson's group and solo shows from 1959 to 1985, and include the following concept exhibitions whose catalogs were issued in very limited numbers: One Month (organized by Seth Siegelaub, March 1969), Letters (organized by Philip Simkin, July 1969), Projects Class (Nova Scotia College of Art and Design, Fall 1969), and Exhibition 557,087 (organized by Lucy Lippard, 1969).
  Other rare printed materials in the series include Vito Acconci's Transference: Roget's Thesaurus, Acconci's periodical 0 to 9 (#6, July 1969), and the avant-garde periodical Aspen (#8, 1970).
  Also included are inventory lists of the published books, periodicals, and phonographs from Robert Smithson's library that have been transferred to off-site storage.
  The series has been arranged by publication type.
  - Books (Box 7)
    - Album 9-68. 2-71, ed. by Instituto Grafico Tiberno, 1971 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Arte Povera, by Germano Celant, 1969 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Breakthrough Fictioneers, ed. by Richard Kostelanetz, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Essaying Essays: Alternative Forms of Exposition, ed. by Richard Kostelanetz, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Great Western Salt Works, ed. by Jack Burnham, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 5)